okay good let's go
instead of the train pulling it tell me
just a little bit bring your shoulder
blades together open your check relax
your fingers
come to your breath try to learn to come
to your breath quickly bring your mind
down into your breath quickly
then try to imagine yourself as you will
be a Buddha and you will see that Buddha
directly for the first time when you see
emptiness directly right after that
experience in in the few hours following
that experience you will see yourself as
you will be a Buddha taking care of an
entire world so I'd like to look at this
Buddha as standing on top of the sky you
know so their feet are the bottom of
their feet are facing the earth but they
are standing high above the atmosphere
standing on the atmosphere venerable
Jigme asked me what should we call a
press that we have for printing Buddhist
books I said let's call it standing on
the sky press so you're standing and you
are looking down at your world that
you're in charge of it's your
responsibility as a Buddhist to focus on
this particular world
and help the beings in this world so you
feel sort of like a mom watching her
child in a crib or something this is
your world to help take care of it and
I'd like you to imagine this Buddha is
like a moon shining full moon
and then down there on the surface of
this earth our bodies of water oceans
makes puddles teardrops and your life of
your moon shines in each one as soon as
the water faces you you appear in the
water like a mirror like stepping in
front of a mirror but those bodies of
water are people who need something so
I'd like you to imagine the Americas
South in North America and choose a city
that you comes to mind
and imagine someone in that city who
needs help today and you decide what
kind of help it could be they dis lost
their boyfriend or girlfriend or husband
or wife or they just found out that
they're very sick to have serious
disease they just lost their job they
don't know what to do you choose a city
and you choose a an imaginary person or
someone you know in the Americas who has
a problem
and then imagine that you step in front
of that mirror and you become someone or
something that could help them maybe a
dear friend or a child who comforts them
or a teacher or a little dog you choose
something and step in front of the
mirror the person who needs you and
imagine you're helping them in a place
in the Americas
and stay in that body of the friend or
the dog in the Americas and then move
your mind to Europe look down on Europe
Western or Eastern Europe and choose the
city
and then decide think of a person who
might need you
let's do the whole strip like Middle
East Africa Europe and think of someone
who needs something to the city create a
imaginary person or think of a person
you know about stay in Syria or
something and come to them is as a
friend protector someone to love reflect
in that mirror in that puddle of water
of a person who needs you but don't let
go that the one in America in the
Americas keep that one going
and create a second
now move your mind to Asia North inside
and at the same time think of any city
to the city ho chi minh Singapore
Jakarta Hong Kong Shanghai Beijing you
choose
imagine a person there who had some
problem don't let go of the first two
bodies you took in the Americas and in
the strip of Europe and Middle East
Africa hold those two now choose a city
in Asia
imagine someone in trouble needs help or
to someone you know and step in front of
that mirror I'm a person in need and
appeared suddenly in their life as a
friend or a teacher or maybe as their
child someone they can love
and enter this third body at the same
time as you keep the other tooth
and keep those three bodies going
helping three different people and bring
your mind back to yourself standing on
the sky those three bodies are still
living helping people but bring your
attention back to yourself that's a good
standing in the sky
and then three long exhales to come back
and then slow the other guys take a good
stretch